<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Emily A Wei on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/author/emily-a-wei/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emily A Wei on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 16:43:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/author/emily-a-wei/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>High-resolution Geophysical and Imagery Data Collected in November 2022 Offshore of Boca Chica Key, FL</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kncmfy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 16:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kncmfy/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Scientists from the U.S. Geological Survey St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center in St. Petersburg, Florida (USGS - SPCSMC), conducted a geophysical and imagery survey around Boca Chica Key, Florida, during November 2022. During this study, multibeam bathymetry and acoustic backscatter data were collected aboard the research vessel (R/V) Sallenger using a Reson T50P Dual Head system. Underwater digital images and global positioning system (GPS) data were collected November 7-12, 2022, within a 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archive of Chirp Subbottom Profile Data Collected in 2022 From Boca Chica Key, Florida</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95m6vht/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:48:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95m6vht/</guid>
      <description>Abstract As part of the Coastal Sediment Availability and Flux and Defense Advanced Research Protection Agency (DARPA) Reefense projects, scientists from the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center (SPCMSC) conducted a nearshore geophysical survey to map the shoreface and inner shelf, as well as characterizing stratigraphy near Boca Chica Key, Florida (FL) in November 2022. The purpose of this study was to conduct a geologic assessment (including bathymetric mapping) of the nearshore ledge off Boca Chica Key, FL, in support of efforts to construct an artificial coral reef offshore of Naval Air Station Key West.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
