<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ecology on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/tags/ecology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ecology on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:03:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/tags/ecology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS) (ver. 2.0, November 2022)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kfftod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kfftod/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Introduced (non-native) species that become established may eventually become invasive, so tracking all introduced species provides a baseline for effective modeling of species trends and interactions, geospatially and temporally. The United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS) (ver. 2.0, November 2022, https://doi.org/10.5066/P9KFFTOD), as of 2022-10-23, is comprised of three lists, for the localities of Alaska (AK, with 545 records), Hawaii (HI, with 5,628 records), and the conterminous (or lower 48) United States (L48, with 8,527 records).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Occurrences of Apis mellifera filamentous virus (AmFV) sequences in public accessions of Apis mellifera and Varroa destructor</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xt6gbe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 04:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xt6gbe/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Honey bees (Apis mellifera), a critical agricultural pollinator in many areas, have a high rate of infection with a large DNA virus, Apis mellifera filamentous virus (AmFV), yet little is known about its ecology or impact on honey bee colonies, other than its ubiquity and apparent low virulence. This study scanned over 5,000 public data sets to detect AmFV sequences in honey bees as well as a parasitic mite of honey bees, Varroa destructor, that is a potential vector of AmFV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brook trout abundance in streams across southern Appalachia from 1958-2021</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9dqid6g/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 04:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9dqid6g/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This Data Release compiles records of brook trout abundance from 745 unique sites across the southern Appalachian mountains from 1958-2021. Records were compiled from 10 institutions, primarily state natural resource agencies. Data were collected from wadeable stream environments with standard backpack electrofishing methods, and observed abundances of adult and juvenile brook trout are reported for each electrofishing pass within sample sites.
Access Points https://www.sciencebase.gov/catalog/item/6439af5dd34ee8d4ade231f8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blacklegged tick nymph densities, tickborne pathogen prevalence, and white-tailed deer densities in eight national parks in the eastern United States from 2014-2022</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9lsi8k9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2023 04:55:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9lsi8k9/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The data presented here are blacklegged tick nymph densities, white-tailed deer densities, and Borrelia burgdorferi (causative agent of Lyme disease) prevalences for eight national parks in the eastern United States from 2014-2022.
Access Points https://www.sciencebase.gov/catalog/item/637cfb9bd34ed907bf73c08c</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American Bird Banding Program Dataset 1960-2023 retrieved 2023-07-12</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p97lqnhy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 21:15:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p97lqnhy/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The North American Bird Banding Program is administered through the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) Bird Banding Laboratory (BBL), Eastern Ecological Science Center at the Patuxent Research Refuge (EESC) and the Bird Banding Office (BBO), Environment and Climate Change Canada (ECCC). The respective banding offices have similar functions and policies and use the same bands, reporting forms and data formats. This long-term dataset (1960-2023) consists of over 83 million bird banding, encounter and recapture records of over 1,000 species covered under the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (MBTA).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estuarine vegetated wetland change scenarios for estuaries in the conterminous United States, 1996–2019</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9u43qeo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 21:36:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9u43qeo/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This data release contains land cover-derived statistics regarding estuarine vegetated wetland area change within estuary drainage areas along the conterminous U.S. This dataset includes net change in estuarine vegetated wetland area based on National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration&amp;rsquo;s (NOAA) Coastal Change Assessment Program (C-CAP) 1996 and 2016 land cover data. Net change was assessed between estuarine vegetated wetlands (i.e., estuarine marshes, mangroves, non-mangrove estuarine woody wetlands, and salt pannes, depending on vegetation coverage and type) and the following other landcover classes: 1) water; 2) unconsolidated shore; 3) freshwater woody wetlands; 4) freshwater marsh; 5) upland; and 6) agriculture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post-fire species point intercept data from four megafires in the Great Basin</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p97b8ti7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:32:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p97b8ti7/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Data set is a combined collection of post-fire species point intercept cover monitoring data across the Murphy 2007 fire, Rush 2012 fire, Holloway 2012 fire, and Soda 2015 fire. Data was collected between 2008 and 2022 by the Bureau of Land Management, US Geological Survey, and Idaho Fish and Wildfire for various purposes. The species data was leveraged to assess post-fire community structure and trajectories.
Access Points https://www.sciencebase.gov/catalog/item/65412f64d34ee4b6e05bcd8f</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) Green Bay, U.S.: Dikes</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9rrv9aj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9rrv9aj/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This dataset is part of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) initiative. These data represent the location of dikes within the Green Bay Restoration Assessment (GBRA) study area. An ArcGIS model (Python script) identified dikes as having a difference in elevation above a certain threshold. If the elevation difference was below a certain threshold, the area was not considered a dike. However, if the difference in elevation between two points was significantly high, then the area was marked as a dike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) Green Bay, U.S.: Degree Flowlines</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9qajrbw/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:23:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9qajrbw/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This dataset is part of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) initiative. These data represent the flowline network in the Green Bay Restoration Assessment (GBRA). It is attributed with the number of disconnections (e.g., road crossings) between the reach and Lake Ontario. The more road crossings on a flowline the more disconnected that area is from the lake and the less suitable it will be for restoration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) Green Bay, U.S.: Composite Model Layers</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p98l86i3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p98l86i3/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This dataset contains all the layers associated with U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) initiative for the Green Bay Restoration Assessment (GBRA) which aims to identify and rank coastal areas with the greatest potential for wetland habitat restoration. Each layer has a unique contribution to the identification of restorable wetlands. The 7 parameters (Parameter 0: Mask, Parameter 1: Hydroperiod, Parameter 2: Wetland Soils, Parameter 3: Flowlines, Parameter 4: Conservation and Recreation Lands, Parameter 5: Impervious Surfaces, and Parameter 6: Land Use) and Index Composite directly correlate to areas that are recommended for restoration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95xl09q/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95xl09q/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Introduced (non-native) species that becomes established may eventually become invasive, so tracking introduced species provides a baseline for effective modeling of species trends and interactions, geospatially and temporally. The United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS) is comprised of three lists, one each for Alaska (AK, with 532 records), Hawaii (HI, with 6,075 records), and the conterminous United States (L48, with 8,657 records). Each list includes introduced (non-native), established (reproducing) taxa that: are, or may become, invasive (harmful) in the locality; are not known to be harmful there; and/or have been used for biological control in the locality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Climate and Soil Moisture Data for the Southern Colorado Plateau Network Parks, 1980 &amp;amp;ndash; 2018 (ver. 1.1, November, 2023)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9wqtbp0/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 16:16:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9wqtbp0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract These data are daily climate, water balance, and soil moisture data for 270 plots in the National Park Service (NPS) Southern Colorado Plateau Network (SCPN) Inventory &amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp; Monitoring (I&amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;amp;M) network. Climate data was collected from a gridded, daily climate dataset, Daymet (https://daymet.ornl.gov/). Climate, alongside field-collected soils (SoilDepthsByPlot.csv) and vegetation information, were then used to drive a point based, daily, multi soil-layer, ecosystem water-balance model, SOILWAT2 (https://github.com/DrylandEcology/SOILWAT2). SCPN plots were established to capture the range of ecosystem conditions present in this network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Lakes Research Vessel Catch (RVCAT) Database</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xvolr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xvolr1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Great Lakes Research Vessel Catch (RVCAT) database is managed at the Great Lakes Science Center (GLSC). RVCAT has been used as the primary data collection tool aboard the GLSC?s research vessel operations across the Great Lakes. Content: The data set has been collected on various vessel operations on all the Great Lakes and select connecting waterways between the years 1930-2021. Data collection begins in early spring and ends in late fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass Carp (Ctenopharyngodon idella) egg capture data from Great Lakes tributaries, 2021-2022 (ver. 1.1, November 2023)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p98f9nsz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 16:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p98f9nsz/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The data includes dates, places, and times of sampling events for eggs of invasive Grass Carp (Ctenopharyngodon idella) in tributaries to the Great Lakes in 2021 and 2022. Reference data on locations and dates sampled, gears used, and effort are included. Developmental stages for a subset of undamaged, fertilized eggs are provided. Tables include common fields to allow for integration into a relational database to aid data extraction and associating data among tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amplified Fragment Length Polymorphism (AFLP) data obtained for 34 long-tailed vole (Microtus longicaudus) individuals at 91 loci</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9yd9m3p/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9yd9m3p/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Prior to removal of pest species from an area, resource managers must determine if re-immigration from another population is possible. Voles inhabiting Saddle Rock on the southern Oregon coast are suspected to be partially responsible for declines in the Leach&amp;rsquo;s storm petrel colony on the island. The island is very close to the mainland, and it is potentially accessible during below-average low tides. USGS scientists Mark Miller and Susan Haig and colleagues used genetic techniques to assess island vole population connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oceanographic conditions at Richardson reef reveal new suitable habitat for cold-water corals</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9pdh0or/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2023 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9pdh0or/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Cold-water corals create complex structures, but our incomplete knowledge of their niche space limits our ability to understand their distribution and therefore the impact of the ecosystem services they provide in the ocean. The Richardson reef complex consists of over 150 km of linear reef tracts within an area of 75 km2 between 700-900 m depth. This reef experiences rapid shifts in temperature, and currents approaching 1 meter per second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea Otter Spraint Data from Kachemak Bay, Katmai National Park and Preserve, Kenai Fjords National Park and Prince William Sound</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9edm6nl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 20:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9edm6nl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract These data are part of the Gulf Watch Alaska (GWA) long-term monitoring program. This dataset consist of observations of sea otter (Enhydra lutris) fecal samples (spraint). Observers examined fresh spraint piles to identify major prey classes in the samples and to determine sea otter diets in the Gulf of Alaska region.
Access Points https://alaska.usgs.gov/products/data.php?dataid=500</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Oystercatcher Nest and Diet Data from Kachemak Bay, Katmai National Park and Preserve, Kenai Fjords National Park, and Prince William Sound</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/f7wh2n5q/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 20:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/f7wh2n5q/</guid>
      <description>Abstract These data are part of the Gulf Watch Alaska (GWA) long-term monitoring program, nearshore monitoring component. The dataset is comprised of six comma separated values (.csv) file exported from a relational database. The data consist of: 1) transect summary, 2) nest details, 3) egg float and stage data, 4) chicks diets, 5) chick diet taxonomy, and 6) Gulf Watch Alaska contributors.
Access Points https://alaska.usgs.gov/products/data.php?dataid=127</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
