<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ginger Tiling-Range on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>http://example.org/author/ginger-tiling-range/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ginger Tiling-Range on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:36:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/author/ginger-tiling-range/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center&#39;s Geologic Core and Sample Database</title>
      <link>http://example.org/10.5066/f7319tr3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 14:36:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/10.5066/f7319tr3/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This application contains information on coral, coral reef, limestone and sediment cores and samples collected by the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center (SPCMSC) or in collaboration with federal, state and university partners. This application contains the geographic location where cores were collected, field survey information, storage location, and if available, associated publications, data analyses, disposition and archival information.
Access Points https://usgs.maps.arcgis.com/apps/webappviewer/index.html?id=2b7d5dbc0be340b9b17f6d94aac5b713</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seafloor elevation change in Maui, St. Croix, St. Thomas, and the Florida Keys</title>
      <link>http://example.org/10.5066/f7wq01w0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:47:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/10.5066/f7wq01w0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center conducted research to quantify the combined effect of all constructive and destructive processes on modern coral reef ecosystems by measuring regional-scale changes in seafloor elevation. USGS staff assessed five coral reef ecosystems in the Atlantic Ocean (Upper and Lower Florida Keys), Caribbean Sea (U.S. Virgin Islands: St. Thomas and Buck Island, St. Croix), and Pacific Ocean (Maui, Hawaii), including both coral-dominated and adjacent, non-coral dominated habitats.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
