<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>10.5061 on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 10.5061 on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 14:53:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adult male birds advance spring migratory phenology faster than females and juveniles across North America</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.m905qfv4v/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.m905qfv4v/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Advances in spring migratory phenology comprise some of the most well-documented evidence for the impacts of climate change on birds. Nevertheless, surprisingly little research has investigated whether birds are shifting their migratory phenology equally across sex and age classes – a question critical to understanding the potential for trophic mismatch. We used 60-years of bird banding data across North America – comprising over 4 million captures in total – to investigate both spring and fall migratory phenology for a total of 98 bird species across sex and age classes, with the exact numbers of species for each analysis depending on season-specific data availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binding and sequestration of poison frog alkaloids by a plasma globulin</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.mkkwh7143/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.mkkwh7143/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Alkaloids are important bioactive molecules throughout the natural world, and in many animals, they serve as a source of chemical defense against predation. Dendrobatid poison frogs bioaccumulate alkaloids from their diet to make themselves toxic or unpalatable to predators. Despite the proposed roles of plasma proteins as mediators of alkaloid trafficking and bioavailability, the responsible proteins have not been identified. We use chemical approaches to show that a ~50 kDa plasma protein is the principal alkaloid binding molecule in blood from poison frogs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data for: A histone demethylase links the loss of plasticity to nongenetic inheritance and morphological change</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.98sf7m0nm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.98sf7m0nm/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Plasticity is a widespread feature of development, enabling phenotypic change based on the environment. Although the evolutionary loss of plasticity has been linked both theoretically and empirically to increased rates of phenotypic diversification, molecular insights into how this process might unfold are generally lacking. Here, we show that a regulator of nongenetic inheritance links evolutionary loss of plasticity in nature to changes in plasticity and morphology as selected in the laboratory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data for: Fabrication and characterization of antibacterial coatings using an amphoteric condensed tannin,Tanfloc</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.gqnk98sv9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.gqnk98sv9/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This dataset presents comprehensive information on the development and characterization of antibacterial polyelectrolyte multilayer (PEM) coatings incorporating tanfloc, a plant-derived condensed tannin polymer with inherent antimicrobial properties. The dataset encompasses experimental data related to the fabrication of PEMs using tanfloc as either a polyanion or a polycation, expanding the versatility of this amphoteric polymer in PEM coatings. Typically, PEMs are formed by combining a polycation and a polyanion with complementary ionic groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: A dynamical model of growth and maturation in Drosophila</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.q573n5tq2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.q573n5tq2/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The decision to stop growing and mature into an adult is a critical point in development that determines adult body size, impacting multiple aspects of an adult’s biology. In many animals, growth-cessation is a consequence of hormone release that appears to be tied to attainment of particular body size or condition. Nevertheless, the size-sensing mechanism animals use to initiate hormone synthesis is poorly understood. Here we develop a simple mathematical model of growth cessation in Drosophila melanogaster, which is ostensibly triggered by attainment of a critical weight early in the last instar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Genetic signatures of lineage fusion closely resemble population decline</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.1jwstqk11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.1jwstqk11/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Accurate interpretation of the genetic signatures of past demographic events is crucial for reconstructing evolutionary history. Lineage fusion (complete merging, resulting in a single panmictic population) is a special case of secondary contact that is seldom considered. Here, the circumstances under which lineage fusion can be distinguished from population size constancy, growth, bottleneck, and decline were investigated. Multi-locus haplotype data were simulated under models of lineage fusion with different divergence versus sampling lag times (D:L ratios).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Integrated species distribution models to account for sampling biases and improve range wide occurrence predictions</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.k98sf7mdg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.k98sf7mdg/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Aim Species distribution models (SDMs) that integrate presence-only and presence-absence data offer a promising avenue to improve information on species’ geographic distributions. The use of such ‘integrated SDMs’ on a species range-wide extent has been constrained by the often-limited presence-absence data and by the heterogeneous sampling of the presence-only data. Here, we evaluate integrated SDMs for studying species ranges with a novel expert range map-based evaluation. We build a new understanding about how integrated SDMs address issues of estimation accuracy and data deficiency and thereby offer advantages over traditional SDMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: programming co-assembled peptide nanofiber morphology via anionic amino acid type: insights from molecular dynamics simulations</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.5mkkwh7bp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.5mkkwh7bp/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Co-assembling peptides can be crafted into supramolecular biomaterials for use in biotechnological applications, such as cell culture scaffolds, drug delivery, biosensors, and tissue engineering. Peptide co-assembly refers to the spontaneous organization of two different peptides into a supramolecular architecture. Here we use molecular dynamics simulations to quantify the effect of anionic amino acid type on co-assembly dynamics and nanofiber structure in binary CATCH(+/-) peptide systems. CATCH peptide sequences follow a general pattern: CQCFCFCFCQC, where all C’s are either a positively charged or a negatively charged amino acid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Soil phosphorus drawdown by perennial bioenergy cropping systems in the Midwestern US</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.dfn2z355r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.dfn2z355r/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Without fertilization, harvest of perennial bioenergy cropping systems diminishes soil nutrient stocks, yet the time course of nutrient drawdown has not often been investigated. We analyzed phosphorus (P) inputs (fertilization and atmospheric deposition) and outputs (harvest and leaching losses) over seven years in three representative biomass crops—switchgrass (Panicum virga­tum L.), miscanthus (Miscanthus X giganteus) and hybrid poplar trees (Populus nigra X P. maximowiczii) – as well as in no-till corn (maize; Zea mays L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: The role of mutation bias in adaptive molecular evolution: insights from convergent changes in protein function</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.2256f38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.2256f38/</guid>
      <description>Abstract An underexplored question in evolutionary genetics concerns the extent to which mutational bias in the production of genetic variation influences outcomes and pathways of adaptive molecular evolution. In the genomes of at least some vertebrate taxa, an important form of mutation bias involves changes at CpG dinucleotides: If the DNA nucleotide cytosine (C) is immediately 5’ to guanine (G) on the same coding strand, and if the C is methylated, then C→T and G→A mutations occur at an elevated rate relative to mutations at non-CpG sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data from: Wildlife fecal microbiota exhibit community stability across a semi-controlled longitudinal non-invasive sampling experiment</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.v6wwpzh2b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.v6wwpzh2b/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Wildlife microbiome studies are being used to assess microbial links with animal health and habitat. The gold standard of sampling microbiomes directly from captured animals is ideal for limiting potential abiotic influences on microbiome composition, yet fails to leverage the many benefits of non-invasive sampling. Application of microbiome-based monitoring for rare, endangered, or elusive species creates a need to non-invasively collect scat samples shed into the environment. Since controlling sample age is not always possible, the potential influence of time-associated abiotic factors was assessed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drought tolerant grassland species are generally more resistant to competition</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.1jwstqk1x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.1jwstqk1x/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Plant populations are limited by resource availability and exhibit physiological trade-offs in resource acquisition strategies. These trade-offs may constrain the ability of populations to exhibit fast growth rates under water limitation and high cover of neighbors. However, traits that confer drought tolerance may also confer resistance to competition. It remains unclear how fitness responses to these abiotic conditions and biotic interactions combine to structure grassland communities and how this relationship may change along a gradient of water availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foraging behavior of tagged rock ants (Temnothorax rugatulus)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.xksn02vn0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.xksn02vn0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Technological advances continue to push the boundaries of scientific inquiry in animal behavior. One such development is the emergence of automated tracking systems, which enable the collection of high-resolution spatio-temporal information for animals. Although tag-based tracking systems provide valuable insights into animal movement and collective behavior, the attachment of devices can have detrimental effects in some cases. Here, we investigated the effects of recently developed miniature tracking tags using the rock ant, Temnothorax rugatulus, as a model system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mRI: multi-modal 3d human pose estimation dataset using mmwave, rgb-d, and inertial sensors</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.9ghx3ffpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.9ghx3ffpp/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The ability to estimate 3D human body pose and movement, also known as human pose estimation~(HPE), enables many applications for home-based health monitoring, such as remote rehabilitation training. Several possible solutions have emerged using sensors ranging from RGB cameras, depth sensors, millimeter-Wave (mmWave) radars, and wearable inertial sensors. Despite previous efforts on datasets and benchmarks for HPE, few datasets exploit multiple modalities and focus on home-based health monitoring. To bridge this gap, we present mRI, a multi-modal 3D human pose estimation dataset with mmWave, RGB-D, and Inertial Sensors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observation of mHz-level cooperative Lamb shifts in an optical atomic clock</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.wpzgmsbtj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.wpzgmsbtj/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We report on the direct observation of resonant electric dipole-dipole interactions in a cubic array of atoms in the many-excitation limit. The interactions, mediated by single-atom couplings to the shared electromagnetic vacuum, are shown to produce spatially-dependent cooperative Lamb shifts when spectroscopically interrogating the mHz-wide optical clock transition in strontium-87. We show that the ensemble-averaged shifts can be suppressed below the level of evaluated systematic uncertainties for state-of-the-art optical atomic clocks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Snow depth, temperature, and residual forage experienced by migrating mule deer during autumn (2011–2020), Wyoming, USA</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.c866t1gdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.c866t1gdc/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Growing evidence supports the hypothesis that temperate herbivores surf the green wave of emerging plants during spring migration. Despite the importance of autumn migration, few studies have conceptualized resource tracking of temperate herbivores during this critical season. We adapted the Frost Wave Hypothesis (FWH), which posits that animals pace their autumn migration to reduce exposure to snow but increase acquisition of forage. We tested the FWH in a population of mule deer in Wyoming, USA by tracking the autumn migrations of n = 163 mule deer that moved 15–288 km from summer to winter range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature-dependent competitive outcomes between the fruit flies Drosophila santomea and D. yakuba</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.bk3j9kd8t/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.bk3j9kd8t/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We use these data to test whether temperature can indirectly affect the fitness of Drosophila santomea and D. yakuba by altering interspecific competitive outcomes. We show that, when raised in isolation, both D. santomea and D. yakuba display similar variation in relative fitness across temperatures of 18°C, 22°C, and 25°C. However, D. santomea has higher fitness than D. yakuba when experiencing interspecific competition at 18°C, while the inverse is true at 25°C.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trait-based sensitivity of large mammals to a catastrophic tropical cyclone: DNA metabarcoding data</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.7wm37pvzv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.7wm37pvzv/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Extreme weather events perturb ecosystems and increasingly threaten biodiversity1. Ecologists emphasize the need to forecast and mitigate the impacts of these incidents, which requires knowledge of how risk is distributed among species and environments, but the scale and unpredictability of extreme events complicates assessment1–4. These challenges are compounded for large animals (‘megafauna’), which play crucial ecological roles but are hard to study5. Traits such as body size, dispersal ability, and habitat affiliation are among the hypothesized determinants of animals’ vulnerability to natural hazards1,6,7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty years of Salix height in response to experimental manipulation of browsing and water table, northern range of Yellowstone National Park</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.sqv9s4n7n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.sqv9s4n7n/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This respository contains multiple datasets collected during a 20 year investigation of the responses of willow (Salix spp.) communities in Yellowstone National Park after the restoration of large carnivores. The study sought to understand whether the restoration of wolves to the food web cause a change in the state of willow communities that occured while wolves were absent. Each dataset has a corresonding file of metadata.
Methods Sampling and experimental designs and methods used to collect the data were described in Hobbs, N.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
