<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Colin Doolan on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/author/colin-doolan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Colin Doolan on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:11:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/author/colin-doolan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Geochemistry of Utica Shale Play and other Appalachian produced waters</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9an5gj0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:11:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9an5gj0/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Citation Note: These data were collected as part of a research study published in Environmental Science and Technology. Please reference the following paper when citing these data. Blondes, M.S., Shelton, J.L., Engle, M.A., Trembly, J.P., Doolan, C.A., Jubb, A.M., Chenault, J.M., Rowan, E.L., Haefner, R.J., and Mailot, B.E., 2020, Utica Shale Play Oil and Gas Brines: Geochemistry and Factors Influencing Wastewater Management: Environmental Science &amp;amp; Technology, https://dx.doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.0c02461. The Utica and Marcellus Shale Plays in the Appalachian Basin are the 4th and 1st largest natural gas producing plays in the United States.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States Gulf Coast Basin Curated Wells and Logs Database (ver. 2.0, November 2023)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95bnwt3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 18:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95bnwt3/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The United States Gulf Coast Basin Curated Wells and Logs Database (CWLDB) is an online repository with stratigraphic information for petroleum wells in the United States portion of the onshore Gulf of Mexico Basin that provides several of the following attributes: a) deep penetrations (generally, total depth of 10,000 feet or more), b) high quality and diverse geophysical well log suites, c) lithostratigraphic logs, d) biostratigraphic units (biozones) and reports, and/or e) core or cuttings samples.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
