<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Zachery W Fehr on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/author/zachery-w-fehr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zachery W Fehr on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:47:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/author/zachery-w-fehr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Projected Seafloor Elevation Change and Relative Sea Level Rise Near St. Croix, U.S. Virgin Islands 25, 50, 75, and 100 Years from 2014</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9zpzxkf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:47:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9zpzxkf/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center conducted research to quantify bathymetric changes near Buck Island and St. Croix, U.S. Virgin Islands. Changes in seafloor elevation were calculated using historical bathymetric point data from the 1980s (see Yates and others, 2017a) and light detection and ranging (lidar)-derived data acquired in 2014 (NOAA, 2015) using methods outlined in Yates and others (2017b). An elevation change analysis between the 1980s and 2014 data was performed to quantify and map historical impacts to seafloor elevation and to determine elevation-change statistics for 12 habitat types found near St, Croix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projected Seafloor Elevation Change and Relative Sea Level Rise Surrounding Maui, Hawaii 25, 50, 75, and 100 Years from 1999</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9diyqv4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9diyqv4/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center conducted research to quantify bathymetric changes surrounding Maui, Hawaii. Changes in seafloor elevation were calculated using historical bathymetric point data from the 1960s (see Yates and others, 2017a) and light detection and ranging (lidar)-derived data acquired in 1999 (NOAA, 2013) using methods outlined in Yate and others (2017b). An elevation change analysis between the 1960s and 1999 data was performed to quantify and map historical impacts to seafloor elevation and to determine elevation-change statistics for 12 habitat types found surrounding Maui.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projected Seafloor Elevation Change and Relative Sea Level Rise Near St. Thomas, U.S. Virgin Islands 25, 50, 75, and 100 Years from 2014</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xx37mp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:44:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xx37mp/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) St. Petersburg Coastal and Marine Science Center conducted research to quantify bathymetric changes near St. Thomas, U.S. Virgin Islands. Changes in seafloor elevation were calculated using historical bathymetric point data from the 1960s and 1970s (see Yates and others, 2017a) and light detection and ranging (lidar)-derived elevation data acquired in 2014 (NOAA, 2015) using methods outlined in Yates and others (2017b). An elevation change analysis between the historical and 2014 data was performed to quantify and map historical impacts to seafloor elevation and to determine elevation-change statistics for 18 habitat types found near St.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
