<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Environmental Health on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/tags/environmental-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environmental Health on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:03:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/tags/environmental-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS) (ver. 2.0, November 2022)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kfftod/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 11:03:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kfftod/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Introduced (non-native) species that become established may eventually become invasive, so tracking all introduced species provides a baseline for effective modeling of species trends and interactions, geospatially and temporally. The United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS) (ver. 2.0, November 2022, https://doi.org/10.5066/P9KFFTOD), as of 2022-10-23, is comprised of three lists, for the localities of Alaska (AK, with 545 records), Hawaii (HI, with 5,628 records), and the conterminous (or lower 48) United States (L48, with 8,527 records).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling information and water-quality data collected during viable avian influenza virus sampling in Iowa wetlands, 2022</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9y9ezi9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 20:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9y9ezi9/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Data sets containing: (1) sampling information and equipment, (2) precipitation and air temperature data from Iowa counties containing wetlands sampled, (3) water quality measurements from Iowa wetlands sampled, (4) quality assurance quality control sample result information, and (4) similarities between the highly pathogenic H5N1 virus water sequence and other highly pathogenic avian influenza H5N1 viruses sequenced from poultry and wild birds in Iowa.
Access Points https://www.sciencebase.gov/catalog/item/6446cc2fd34ee8d4adec6c45</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) Green Bay, U.S.: Dikes</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9rrv9aj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 15:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9rrv9aj/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This dataset is part of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) Great Lakes Coastal Wetland Restoration Assessment (GLCWRA) initiative. These data represent the location of dikes within the Green Bay Restoration Assessment (GBRA) study area. An ArcGIS model (Python script) identified dikes as having a difference in elevation above a certain threshold. If the elevation difference was below a certain threshold, the area was not considered a dike. However, if the difference in elevation between two points was significantly high, then the area was marked as a dike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95xl09q/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 10:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p95xl09q/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Introduced (non-native) species that becomes established may eventually become invasive, so tracking introduced species provides a baseline for effective modeling of species trends and interactions, geospatially and temporally. The United States Register of Introduced and Invasive Species (US-RIIS) is comprised of three lists, one each for Alaska (AK, with 532 records), Hawaii (HI, with 6,075 records), and the conterminous United States (L48, with 8,657 records). Each list includes introduced (non-native), established (reproducing) taxa that: are, or may become, invasive (harmful) in the locality; are not known to be harmful there; and/or have been used for biological control in the locality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Farmington Lake Sediment Descriptions, Total Sediment Chemistry, and Batch Experiment Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kr7nsl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 04:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9kr7nsl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract These datasets provide information about the physical properties, total sediment chemistry, and batch experiment chemistry (to evaluate element mobility) of sediment cores from the Farmington Lake reservoir in Farmington, NM. The sediment cores were collected in November 2019.
Access Points https://www.sciencebase.gov/catalog/item/5e41d3e5e4b0edb47be63c63</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Lakes Research Vessel Catch (RVCAT) Database</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xvolr1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 08:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9xvolr1/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The Great Lakes Research Vessel Catch (RVCAT) database is managed at the Great Lakes Science Center (GLSC). RVCAT has been used as the primary data collection tool aboard the GLSC?s research vessel operations across the Great Lakes. Content: The data set has been collected on various vessel operations on all the Great Lakes and select connecting waterways between the years 1930-2021. Data collection begins in early spring and ends in late fall.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
