<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>University of New Mexico on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/affiliations/university-of-new-mexico/</link>
    <description>Recent content in University of New Mexico on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/affiliations/university-of-new-mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Data from: The role of mutation bias in adaptive molecular evolution: insights from convergent changes in protein function</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.2256f38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.2256f38/</guid>
      <description>Abstract An underexplored question in evolutionary genetics concerns the extent to which mutational bias in the production of genetic variation influences outcomes and pathways of adaptive molecular evolution. In the genomes of at least some vertebrate taxa, an important form of mutation bias involves changes at CpG dinucleotides: If the DNA nucleotide cytosine (C) is immediately 5’ to guanine (G) on the same coding strand, and if the C is methylated, then C→T and G→A mutations occur at an elevated rate relative to mutations at non-CpG sites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drought tolerant grassland species are generally more resistant to competition</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.1jwstqk1x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5061/dryad.1jwstqk1x/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Plant populations are limited by resource availability and exhibit physiological trade-offs in resource acquisition strategies. These trade-offs may constrain the ability of populations to exhibit fast growth rates under water limitation and high cover of neighbors. However, traits that confer drought tolerance may also confer resistance to competition. It remains unclear how fitness responses to these abiotic conditions and biotic interactions combine to structure grassland communities and how this relationship may change along a gradient of water availability.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
