<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Animals/vertebrates on Landingpage-in-a-Box</title>
    <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/tags/animals/vertebrates/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Animals/vertebrates on Landingpage-in-a-Box</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/tags/animals/vertebrates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Data for Bar-tailed Godwits (Limosa lapponica)</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9a9byqw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 01:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9a9byqw/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This metadata document describes the data contained in the &amp;ldquo;rawData&amp;rdquo; folder of this data package. This data package contains all data collected by the Argos System from 63 satellite transmitters attached to Bar-tailed Godwits on their breeding range in arctic and western Alaska, 2005-2010. Five data files are included in the &amp;ldquo;rawData&amp;rdquo; folder of this data package. Two data files (with identical content) contain the raw Argos DIAG (Diagnostic) data, one in the legacy verbose ASCII format and one in a tabular Comma Separate Value (CSV) format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Detection and Characterization of Highly Pathogenic H5N1 Avian Influenza Viruses in Wild Birds Inhabiting Western Alaska Provides Evidence for Three Independent Viral Introductions</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9lph8zq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 22:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9lph8zq/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This data set describes three independent viral introductions of Highly pathogenic H5N1 avian influenza viruses into Alaska.
Access Points https://alaska.usgs.gov/products/data.php?dataid=606</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea Otter Spraint Data from Kachemak Bay, Katmai National Park and Preserve, Kenai Fjords National Park and Prince William Sound</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9edm6nl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 20:27:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/p9edm6nl/</guid>
      <description>Abstract These data are part of the Gulf Watch Alaska (GWA) long-term monitoring program. This dataset consist of observations of sea otter (Enhydra lutris) fecal samples (spraint). Observers examined fresh spraint piles to identify major prey classes in the samples and to determine sea otter diets in the Gulf of Alaska region.
Access Points https://alaska.usgs.gov/products/data.php?dataid=500</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Black Oystercatcher Nest and Diet Data from Kachemak Bay, Katmai National Park and Preserve, Kenai Fjords National Park, and Prince William Sound</title>
      <link>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/f7wh2n5q/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 20:12:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datapurifier.github.io/landingpage-in-a-box/10.5066/f7wh2n5q/</guid>
      <description>Abstract These data are part of the Gulf Watch Alaska (GWA) long-term monitoring program, nearshore monitoring component. The dataset is comprised of six comma separated values (.csv) file exported from a relational database. The data consist of: 1) transect summary, 2) nest details, 3) egg float and stage data, 4) chicks diets, 5) chick diet taxonomy, and 6) Gulf Watch Alaska contributors.
Access Points https://alaska.usgs.gov/products/data.php?dataid=127</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
